Shinji Pons - Senior Product Designer

Toulouse, France +33 07 44 74 31 34 hello@shinjipons.com

Links Portfolio https://shinjipons.com

Linkedin https://linkedin.com/in/shinjipons/

Github https://github.com/shinjipons/

Layers https://layers.to/shinjipons

Summary

I'm a results-driven product designer with 10 years of experience designing complex desktop software applications for creative professionals in the automotive, video game and animation industries.

Areas of Expertise

Product Design Figma

UI/UX Design Blender Python

Wireframing Autodesk Alias JavaScript

Prototyping 3D Modelling HTML/CSS

Employment History

Jun 2023 - May 2024

Senior Product Designer - Ragdoll Dynamics

Toulouse, France

Midjourney

- Sole designer at an early-stage company revolutionizing 3D character animation through rigid body simulation.
- Designed a new standalone desktop application and created a comprehensive design system from the ground up.
- · Contributed to the testing and release of the Ragdoll Dynamics for Blender add-on.
- · Prototyped interface elements using ImGui integrated via JavaScript.
- Improved customer processes by adopting Attio, enhancing communication and customer relationship management.

Jan 2021 - May 2023

Senior Experience Designer - Electronic Arts

Guildford, United Kingdom

- Enhanced tools and workflows for over 5000 professionals using Frostbite, EA's proprietary game engine.
- Shaped future character creation workflows for AAA titles including Skate, EA FC, and UFC.
- Focused on character workflows for EA Sports & Racing titles, optimizing runtime deformation and mass loading of character assets.

May 2019 - Dec 2021

Senior Product Designer - The LEGO Group

Billund, Denmark

- · Modernized LEGO Digital Designer Pro, the in-house 3D CAD-like modeller.
- Led design experience leveraging brick data for improved connectivity, pricing, and collision detection.
- Reduced repetitive task time by up to 90% through redesigning essential tools.
- Built a fully digital pipeline from concept to marketing for 70% of new LEGO products.

Employment History (continued)		
Jun 2017 - May 2019	Experience Designer - Autodesk	Hanover, Germany
	 Directed design for fast concept modelling and computational leading 3D CAD software. Led design of subdivision modelling features in Alias 2020. Conducted user testing workshops with over 60 professional studios like Volvo and Toyota. Delivered tools that sped up concept design finalization by 6 	users from top automotive
Apr 2016 - Apr 2017	Experience Designer - Thomson Reuters	London, United Kingdom
	 Designed prototypes and features using natural language processing to automate risk detection in the World-Check Risk Intelligence product. 	
Feb 2015 - Nov 2015	User Experience Designer - Microsoft	London, United Kingdom
	 Created interactive experiences in public spaces to raise awareness of the Windows Devices brand. 	
Dec 2014 - Feb 2015	User Interface Designer - Style.com	London, United Kingdom
	 Designed branding and user interface elements for a fashion, travel, and luxury content and e-commerce platform. 	
Education		
2010 - 2014	London College of Communication	London, United Kingdom
	Bachelor of Arts, Graphic & Media Design (First Class Honours)	
Languages	French Native proficiency	
	English Native proficiency	
Internships		
Sep 2014 - Dec 2014	Graphic Design Intern - Barnbrook	London, United Kingdom
	Designed, laid out, and art-worked for clients including Art Ba	asel and David Bowie.
Oct 2012 - Jan 2013	Graphic Design Intern - Ateliers Jean Nouvel	Paris, France
	 Designed icon and typographic signage systems for the Louvre Abu Dhabi (in French, English, and Arabic). 	